Guide to the Carla Stellweg Papers M1752
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 10. Accession 2015-145. Additional Materials
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 1 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 113, Folder 10)
    Various artist catalogs with info and research materials including the work of participating/prospective artists for the exhibition, The Faraway Nearby, a multi-media show of Finnish artists at White Box, NY, curated by Carla Stellweg (March 30-April 22, 2006) along with invites and a Digital Video Disc.
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 2 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 113, Folder 11)
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 3 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 113, Folder 12)
    Various artist catalogs with info and research materials including the work of participating/prospective artists for the exhibition, The Faraway Nearby, a multi-media show of Finnish artists at White Box, NY, curated by Carla Stellweg (March 30-April 22, 2006) along with invites.
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 4 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    Various artist catalogs with info and research materials including the work of participating/prospective artists for the exhibition, The Faraway Nearby, a multi-media show of Finnish artists at White Box, NY, curated by Carla Stellweg (March 30-April 22, 2006) along with invites, photographs and a Digital Video Disc.
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 5 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 6 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 7 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Morton Casa de Subastas Mexican Art auction catalog wit Lot 153, Francisco Toledo's Toledo/Sahagún (1974), October 1, 2015 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Rago Post-War and Contemporary Art auction catalog with Lots 655-770 from the Collection of George and Carla Stellweg, November 15, 2014 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    including a bio-blurb. Digital Supplement: video of Carla Stellweg.
  - Morton Casa de Subastas Latin American Art auction catalog with Lot 45, Alfredo Castañeda's San Hugolino (c. 1976), November 20, 2014 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - PHILLIPS Latin American Art auction catalog with Lots 37, 41, 64, 71, 103, 111, 112 and 121 from the Collection of George and Carla Stellweg, November 24, 2014 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Morton Casa de Subastas Modern and Contemporary Art auction catalog with Lot 142, Jan Hendrix's Valley of the Brave 237 (1980), March 1, 2015 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    Lot 142 appears on p. 104.
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg and parents, 1935-1956 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Carla Stellweg fashion photographs, 1960s (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Carla Stellweg fashion photographs, 1960s (Flat-box 120, Folder 1)
  - Carla Stellweg fashion photographs, 1960s (Flat-box 120, Folder 2)
  - Various photographs and newspaper articles, 1962-1973 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    Various photos and newspaper articles re: Venice Biennial; Expo67; Carla Stellweg passport photos; Amazon trip after Lima Peru Symposium; Salon Independiente; Cheerleading, Mexico Salon Independiente soccer teams; various with Fernando Gamboa; My loft during making of Contrabienal; with Arnold Belkin (husband from 1964-67?); and photo of Carla Stellweg with Gamboa (next to Carla Stellweg on L), Louise Bourgeois (far R) and Willem de Kooning (forefront) at the Guggenheim’s Willem de Kooning Award Presentation Reception (1979); etc.
  - Various photographs and newspaper articles, 1967-1981, 1996-1999 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Holland and Italy trip, 1969-1970, 1982-1983 (Box 115, Folder 8)
    The trip was whilst working on the Contrabienal Book distribution in Europe.
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg with parents in Mexico and Switzerland, 1970-1979 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    Carla Stellweg with her parents in Patzcuaro, Michoacán; Switzerland (1972); Carla Stellweg’s parents 25th Anniversary in Mexico (1971); Mayan ruins Usumacinta River, Chiapas, MX (1971)
  - Photographs of Japan and trip around the world for the Mexico pavilion during Exposition '70, 1969-1971 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    Mexico pavilion Expo ’70; trip to Hong Kong, Taiwan, Indonesia, Bali, Thailand, Vietnam and Cambodia with Fernando Gamboa.
  - Photographs of Venice Biennial and Lucca, Italy, 1978-1979 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    Venice Biennial and Lucca, Italy; Carla Stellweg, son George Stellweg, Roger Welch, and Emma Cecilia Garcia (Krinsky) and Marta Chilindrón.
  - Various photographs (part 1 of 3), 1970-2008 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    1976 – 70 Mexico trip, beach, etc.; 1970’s – 1980’s Polaroid pictures; 1980’s Mexico trip w/Gabriel Orozco; 1989 Bellport, Long Island house – Carla Stellweg with her mother and friends (some NY art world celebs)
  - Various photographs (part 2 of 3), 1970-2008 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    1990’s Carla Stellweg Gallery on Broadway; 1990’s Mexico trip with Spencer Throckmorton, Manuel Alvarez-Bravo, etc.; 1990’s Pictures of artworks by Elizondo, Palacios and outsider artists; 1994 Europe Brussels Art Fair and Paris. Includes negatives.
  - Various photographs (part 3 of 3), 1970-2008 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    1998-2001 Blue Star period including trip to Marfa; 2001 Back to NY from Blue Star; 2001 or 2002 New Years Eve, including images w/ Berta Sichel, Colette, Marta Chilindrón.; 2002 Thanksgiving pics with Thomas McEvilley, Dennis Oppenheim, Edward Leffingwell, Mary Beth Edelson, Eduardo Costa, Mike Casey, Paco Cao, Biliana and Ali Aboutaam, etc.; 2002 87 East Houston pics – location of 36 years, plus 1989-1997 was also location of the Carla Stellweg Gallery; 2008 Carla Stellweg promo pics (by Barbara Lebow)
  - Carla Stellweg with various artists and celebrities, 1980-2012 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    Carla Stellweg with various artists and celebrities, including Rufino Tamayo, Mario Moya Palencia (Mexican Ambassador to U.N.), novelist Carlos Fuentes, artist Jaime Davidovich, Axel Stein (Head of Latin American Art Deptartment at Sotheby’s), Carlos Zerpa’s wife, artist Adolfo Riesra, Patricia Sloane, Manuel Alvarez Bravo, Adolfo Patiño, and more.
  - Photographs with Andy Warhol, 1980s (Box 116, Folder 6)
    Photographs with Andy Warhol, Fred Hughes, Gerard Malanga and Agustin Legorreta and his wife – at VIP opening reception of Images of Mexico exhibition Banco Nacional de Mexico’s Collection at Manufacturers Hanover Trust building on Park Avenue CATALOG IS ALREADY AT STANFORD - EITHER IN BOX #31 or #32.
  - Photographs from the opening of the Tamayo Museum, 1981 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    Photographs from the opening of the Tamayo Museum with Fernando Gamboa, Carla Stellweg, Rufino Tamayo and President Lopez Portillo along with large color pic of Carla Stellweg with Fernando Gamboa in Plaza de Mexico fiesta brava - bullfights.
  - Stellweg-Seguy Gallery photographs, 1983-1984 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    Includes negatives.
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg with Margarita Herrera and Fernando Gamboa, 1986 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    Carla Stellweg with Margarita Herrera and Fernando Gamboa (and Conchita?) in the Yucatán, Uxmal and Chichen-Itza.
  - Photographs of Chateau Vignelaure, La Provence, France, 1986 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    Chateau Vignelaure, La Provence, France showing Mr. and Mrs. Brunet owners of vineyard with whom traded 1,500 bottles of their best Bordeaux.
  - Photographs of Bellport, Long Island house with Rafael Montañez Ortiz and Yishai and Irene Jusidman, 1988 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Bellport house with Les and Catherine Levine, 1988-1995 (Box 116, Folder 12)
    Photographs are during an Indonesian feast Carla Stellweg's mother prepared. Includes negatives.
  - Photographs of MoCHA symposium; Guadalajara Art Fair; Carlos Garaicoa; Rooted Visions show; Frida book, 1988-1995 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - Various photographs, 1990-1999 (Box 116, Folder 14)
    Various photos of: Carla Stellweg with Julio Galán; with Elena Poniatowska, Claudia Madrazo, Graciela Reyes Retana MUNAL, Mexico opening of Frida Kahlo photographs my collection; Various Art Fairs (including Wiegersma Art Basel Art Fair); Carla Stellweg in Austin, Texas; Carla Stellweg during her “Blue Star” period; and related to Vrej Baghoomian Gallery.
  - Photographs of MARCO Monterrey trip with Blue Star patrons, 1990s (Box 117, Folder 1)
    see private and public collections
  - Photographs of gallery, art, family and art fairs around the world, 1994-1995 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Japan trip for Frida Kahlo exhibition and book; rooftop of Carla Stellweg's loft, 1990s (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Negatives (only) of gallery shows and artists, 1990s (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Negatives (only) of 87 East Houston Street, New York City barbeque; Sotheby's lecture; Mexico trip, 1990s (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Documenta Kassel photographs, circa 1992 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg with cat, Chula, in Bellport, Long Island house, 1992 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg with mother and art world celebrities at Carla Stellweg Gallery summer house, Bellport, Long Island, 1993 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Juan Acha visit; blizzard; Miami Art Fair, 1993-1999 (Box 117, Folder 9)
    with Juan Acha at Christmas time, along with blizzard photographs from the front of Carla Stellweg building on East Houston Street, New York City.
  - Photographs of Christmas in California and Mammoth, California mountain skiing and snowmobiling, with (son) George Stellweg and Judy Bellacicco, 1994 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg Gallery at Miami Art Fair and George Stellweg and Judy Bellacicco at Carla Stellweg dinner in New York City, 1994 (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Guadalajara Art Fair; Ismael Vargas; Xochicalco Pyramids with Tona (Giandomenico Tonatiuh Pellizzi), 1994 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg with various art world figures, including Eduardo Costa, Liliana Porter and Judith Gutierrez, 1980s, 1994-2009 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Oma's 80th birthday party, April, 1995 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Narrowsburg summer (1995); Arco Madrid (1996); Drik and Saar van Leusden visit (1996 and 2001) (Cri Stellweg's grandchildren), 1995-2001 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Jaime Palacios' show; WRW work; Angel Lopez (gallery assistant) and more of Chula, the art loving cat, 1994-1995 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    Angel Lopez making crate for works to be shipped to Basel Art Fair, Geneva. Includes negatives.
  - Santa Fe Art Fair; La Chiripada Farm (Carla Stellweg formerly owned, 1972-1975); plus other New Mexico photographs, 1995 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    La Chiripada farm, Dixon, New Mexico (between Taos and Santa Fe on the Embudo River). Includes negatives.
  - Photographs of Santa Fe Art Fair and Ray Graham (Firestone) III/his Carla Stellweg Collection in Albuquerque, 1995 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Bellport and Marina Del Rey - (son) George Stellweg and then-wife Judy Bellacicco with Carla Stellweg and her mom, 1996 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of After MACO Guadalajara Art Fair, R&R at Careyes Beach, Jalisco, Mexico, 1996 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of blizzard in New York City at 87 East Houston Street, 1996 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Carla Stellweg Gallery at Gramercy Art Fair (1996); Carla Stellweg Gallery at Arco Madrid (1997); Carla Stellweg Gallery at Art Miami (1998), 1996-1998 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Carla Stellweg announced as Director of Blue Star, Texas and more Christmas Marina Del Rey, California photographs, 1998-1999 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Venice Biennial and Milan with Bilianna, Alex Missheff etc., 2000s (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Assortment of photographs from Carla Stellweg's White Box period; her with Ed Leffingwell; her visiting Monterrey, Mexico; her with Bilianna in Venice, Italy and more, 2001-2008 (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Steve Posser's Hyde Park, New York spread and environs, 2001 (Box 118, Folder 13)
    At Steven Poser’s Hyde Park spread, raking fall leaves, right after returning from 5 years of Texas with no fall nor winter!
  - Photographs of Summer Holland-Italy trip, 2002 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of Monterrey trip; Marco and the home of Margarita and Guillermo Fernandez Urquiza, 2004 (Box 118, Folder 15)
    Home of Margarita and Guillermo Fernandez de Urquiza, with Jacqueline and Raymond McClellan, Judy Lackritz and Bill Long from San Antonio, Texas (Blue Star Contemporary Art Center patrons).
  - Photographs of Corsica trip with Marieke de Koning and family, 2004 (Box 118, Folder 16)
  - White Box related photographs, 2003-2005 (Box 118, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Miami Bimini Island, Bahamas trip with (son) George Stellweg and his buddies, 2005-2006 (Box 118, Folder 18)
  - Compact Disc of photographs for Carla Stellweg from Barbara Lebow, 2008 (Box 118, Folder 19)
  - Compact Disc of Taller de la Gráfica Popular, Posada, Manilla and Amaral, undated (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Compact Disc and pamphlet from the Keith Sonnier Foundation to support the project, SAC-O-LAIT, 2003 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - City of New York's Department of Cultural Affairs Cultural Development Fund grant final report for White Box, 2012 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Xi Fei's solo exhibition at White Box, 2012 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    Curated by Carla Stellweg with an accompanying catalog for which she wrote an essay.
  - Carla Stellweg presentation for the Fernando Gamboa Homage at the Palacio B.A. Sala Manuel Ponce, 2009-2010 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Background materials for el Museo de Arte Moderno's Arte Visuales facsimile, published in conjunction with Fernando Gamboa: La utopia moderna exhibition, with an essay by Carla Stellweg, 2009 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México - Annual Conference materials, 2008-2011 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Various White Box funding and infrastructural materials, 2006-2012 (Box 119, Folder 8)
    Related to materials in Box 75.
  - Rafael Miranda correspondence, 2011 (Box 119, Folder 9)
  - NYSCA application for White Box's Electronic Media and Film program, MAPS (Media Arts, Performance and Sound), 2012 (Box 119, Folder 10)
  - White Box Benefit Auction: checklist, master Excel workbooks, 2011 (Box 119, Folder 11)
  - Jorge Santana Dissertation from the Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México and related works, 2012-2015 (Box 119, Folder 12)
  - White Box Spring Benefit Auction: checklist, pricelist, committee information and results, 2013 (Box 119, Folder 13)
  - Mexican Symposium Archives: documents and correspondence, 2015 (Box 119, Folder 14)
  - Presentation text and handout materials from Archive Fuera de Lugar seminar at the Ex Teresa Arte Actual, Mexico D.F., 2015 (Box 119, Folder 15)
    Carla Stellweg gave a presentation on archives alongside Martha Wilson and many more speakers. Materials inccude a Compact Disc. A digital presentation will be forthcoming.
  - Negatives, positive film transparencies, Jelly Bean inner negatives and prints of Frida Kahlo (1929-1954) (part 1 of 2), 1980-2009 (Box 119, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, positive film transparencies, Jelly Bean inner negatives and prints of Frida Kahlo (1929-1954) (part 2 of 2), 1980-2009 (Box 119, Folder 17)
  - hard drive [has been imaged] (Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous CDs, DVDs and floppy disks, 1994-2009 (Card-box 122)
    There are 23 CD-Rs and DVD-Rs. There are 66 3.5" floppy disks. Some of the CD-Rs and DVD-Rs are related to exhibitions and shows that are also documented in other locations in the collection. Some of the materials have a brief description from Carla Stellweg explaining the relation to other materials and the context.